Software Engineer

Agile/Scrum

Jenkins

AWS

Cyrois.github.io Cell: 604-363-5700 Home: 604-733-2812 ChanSquaredStudio@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/chancalvink

# **Summary**"

Software Engineer with a passion for learning a plethora of skills that are not solely used for software development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web applications. Well-versed in Java, Agile Methodologies and Quality Assurance. Background in software development with a strong focus in making tasks and processes simple and efficient.

#### **Technical Skills**

#### **Up-to-date Experience**

- Windows/Linux/OSX
- Groovy/Javascript/CSS
- Selenium/Geb/JUnit
- Grails

#### **Past Experience**

- Atlassian Tool Set
- Ant/Maven/Grunt
- SCSS
- Angular

- Python
- C++/C
- MySQL
- PHP

# **Work Experience**

# TuGo

June, 2016 - Current Software Developer

- Developed and executed automated and manual tests to assist in the deployment of applications using Geb. • Completed front end development tasks for public and internal web applications using Grails.
- Conducted code reviews using Bitbucket to learn and provide feedback about changes to the code base.
- Created Jenkins jobs for automatic deployment, such a legacy system that used Ant as a build tool.
- Collaborated with analysts, designers, and developers to create simple, efficient and intuitive user interfaces.
- Acted as Team lead for a project to replace the inventory management system, which was successfully adopted.
- Acted as Scrum master to help the IT department adopt scrum and improve development processes.

# **Global Relay**

## Front End Web Developer (Co-op)

August, 2014 - December, 2014

- Fixed numerous issues in the user interface by using the Sencha5 Javascript framework.
- Fixed numerous layout issues using SCSS and HTML to improve the user interface of the application.
- Improved the runtime speed of the team's internationalization (i18n) tool from 45 to 2 seconds by using Java.
- Created an automated test suite for the i18n tool to ensure proper functionality.
- Added build tasks in Grunt and Maven to simplify the development process, such as automate execution of the i18n
- Conducted code reviews using Crucible to learn and provide feedback about changes to the code base.

## **Global Relay**

# Automation Developer (Co-op)

May, 2014 - September, 2014

- Manually tested new software features and created test suites to be reused in the future.
- Automated test cases in the Selenium framework (Java) to increase the coverage of automated regression tests.
- Found bugs in the application and generated bug reports, which were communicated to the team using Jira.
- Demonstrated to the product owner that a feature is in working order and could be released to the public.
- Conducted code reviews using Crucible, mainly to communicate to others about additions to the test framework.

# **HP Autonomy**

May, 2013 - December, 2013

# Automation Developer (Co-op)

- Created automated test suites to perform functionality, performance and integration tests.
- Added to the existing test framework that was written in Ruby.
- Documented test automation cases, test automation suites, and test scripts.
- Found bugs in the application and generated a bug report, which were communicated to the team using Jira.

# **Technical Projects**

## **QOTD Chrome Plugin**

September, 2017 - Current

- Designed a chrome plugin that display a new quote every day.
- Created an API that would return a new quote every day.

Tweet Saver March, 2016

- Created a web page that would display JSON data as well as have persistent browser states.
- Implemented the web page using Angular and an external Angular library.

UBC Lost-n-Found March, 2016 – April, 2016

- Acted as team leader to spread tasks evenly among the 4 members, stimulate conversation and monitor progress.
- Designed a relational-database for the project and implemented the database using MySQL.
- Created the web page and connected the user-interface to the database using PHP.

# **Recycling Bin Game**

September, 2015 - April, 2016

- Acted as team leader to spread tasks among the team, act as primary contact to clients and lead team meetings.
- Designed the software architecture with one other engineer and developed a modular and efficient system.
- Implemented various software classes using the Python programming language.

#### **Phone Lock Mechanism**

October, 2015 - December, 2015

- Designed a proof of concept Android application, with 2 other students, that required a user to unlock the
  application.
- Implemented an algorithm that will verify a swipe gesture to be a valid unlocking sequence and grant access if so.
- Presented the project to classmates and industry sponsors to explain the significance of our changes in security.

## **Volunteer Work Experience**

# 4<sup>th</sup> Year Graduation Representative

September, 2015 - April, 2016

- Organized essential activities for graduating students such as taking iron ring sizes.
- Created a graduation hoodie specially designed for our graduation year.
- Relayed information from the engineering student council the entire class of electrical and computer engineering.
- Relayed student complaints to the engineering student council to discuss with professors.

#### **Shambhala Music Festival**

August, 2015

- Helped with setup and teardown of pylons, fences and signs
- Guided attendees to parking locations
- Ensured that attendees had fun!

#### **Calgary Food Bank**

August, 2013

- Folded cardboard boxes into shape and taped the bottom of the box closed.
- Packaged boxes with food that would feed a family for several days.

#### **Education**

Agile42 – Scrum Alliance Certified Scrum Master

September 2017

University of British Columbia

Bachelor of Applied Science – Software Engineering

Graduation – April 2016

September, 2011 - April, 2016

## **Awards and Recognition**

### Introduction to Computer Security (Phone lock mechanism)

December, 2015

- Best Design Project
- Best Holistic Approach to Computer Security
- Best Video